<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sweet potato press</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>//</link>
    <atom:link href="//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 20:29:33 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 20:29:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aliester Crowley birth chart analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Aliester Crowley: birth chart analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;click to enlarge&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/crowley/crowley.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/crowley/crowley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

Crowley has a night sect chart as the sun is below the horizon. He has Leo rising with the sun in their fall in libra, his third house. we see here that the topics of the 3rd house are important to his health and security as well as his very being. with a fallen sun we could expect sorrow and difficulties from this point of life, a feeling of not being seen. We also find the benefic of sect Venus in the 3rd. she is under the beams but in her own bounds and domicile, this is known as being in ones chariot. There too is the feeling of being unseen when a planet is under the beams; like a part of life that isn&apos;t as recognizable to the native, yet still she is in her own Egyptian bounds and domicile. she is able to assert herself strongly. it is as if she is drudging up hidden sights from the underworld itself! Venus too rules the sign of Taurus so she imports significations from that house to the 3rd. There is a strong connection between communications and career. Again asserting her ability to bring up from the hidden places, the underworld in the myth of Inanna, to the most public area of life. Suiting for an occultist that brought ceremonial magick into the public eye! The occult was once only for wealthy priests and secret societies. Crowley was born 2 days before an eclipse which is regarded as a mark of eminence or importance. we can also expect eclipses to have a greater effect on him through his life. 

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Examining the sect light, the moon, we see her in the succedent 8th house, in a nocturnal sign, waxing, ruled by the benefic Jupiter, in the bounds of mars, and her triplicity rulers are Mars, Venus, and the moon herself. We find mars exalted in Capricorn, his 6th house. mars is in their joy in the 6th but it is still a cadent house. Venus likewise is in a cadent house. typically with two of the sect lights triplicity lords in cadent houses we would expect one to have a grueling and difficult life but both planets are highly dignified which eases their assault on Crowley&apos;s existence. He struggled with many bouts of ill health throughout his life, some that the doctors declared as fatal - but somehow managed to recover. he also struggled with addictions his entire life while having to work almost non-stop to upkeep his magickal disciplines and livelihood especially when his inheritance ran out. To what degree of success ill leave an open question. We can also inspect the pre-natal syzygy for significations of life, this was a new moon on sep. 29th in libra leading the triplicity lords to be mercury, Saturn, and Jupiter. we find all 3 of them angular with Saturn in his own domicile leading us to suspect that the 2nd half of life may be better though certainly not easy as he is still the counter sect malefic. 

&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; the houses &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd house of Virgo is ruled by mercury in the 4th house Scorpio. the 2nd house is exoterically ones finances and how they are made, esoterically its the inner body, ones organs and the upkeep of the organs. diet, things one needs to be healthy, worldly possessions. it is the gate of hades after all, both the entrance and exit to the underworld, a hidden and mysterious place. we see here  a connection between possessions and foundations, a connection between money and the home. Crowley spent much of his time writing, practicing, and reading from his large library at home. The 4th house is the most private and secret aspect of ones chart and can indicate hidden matters and in this case hidden things are important to Crowley&apos;s finances. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
in the 4th house of Scorpio we find its ruler in the 6th; an exalted mars in Capricorn. there is a connection between his foundations and hard work. Which indeed he spent many sleepless nights writing, doing ritual and engaging in wanton hedonism. funnily enough the ruler of the 6th is in the 7th of relationships. his many &quot;scarlet women&quot; and otherwise. &lt;br /&gt; Scorpio is a mysterious and inward looking water sign that the ancients also associated with hidden matters, the genitals, thievery - and its in this house we find both Jupiter and mercury. Jupiter is importing 5th and 8th house matters, creativity, death, and inheritance. The 4th is also ones parents, especially the father - and its from his father he received a massive inheritance in his youth. He used this money to spread his philosophy and religion across the world, his creative output like book publishing and of course drugs and sex(decided 5th house topics) Mercury imports finances and community, reaffirming his use of funds to spread his message. &lt;br /&gt; Mercury will be stationing retrograde in his chart within 7 days of birth and preparing to make a heliacal set(becoming hidden under the rays of the sun and no longer appearing in the western sky) this is considered to be a great burst of energy with the station but a general weakening overtime - but this once again reasserts the importance of hidden things. the 4th house can also be about endings and death which indeed his work and writing heavily centers around. In his written ritual instruction &quot;Liber HHH&quot; he gives many meditations on death. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;  
&lt;div&gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/crowley/c1.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&apos;LIBER HHH SVB FIGVRA CCCXLI&apos; Ch. II&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/crowley/c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 &lt;br /&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;This is but one of numerous examples of a mystical relationships with death, the subsequent rebirth, and hidden things. A true exposition would fill tomes- and that is exactly what he did. 
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Crowley placed a high importance on his relationships with women in his life but ultimately left them ruined and in despair -a theme we see repeating through out his life. so its appropriate that we find his 7th house ruled by Saturn with Saturn in their own place. A powerful Saturn but still the malefic out of sect, they are receiving a superior trine from Venus and square from Jupiter which both lessen Saturn&apos;s capability to inflict difficulty but none-the less his relationships were short lasting and greatly damaging to them as well as himself and his reputation.
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The 8th house is Pisces ruled by Jupiter in the 4th. his lot of fortune is here suggesting luck in matters of shared finance, death, and inheritance. The moon is also here, being the luminary of sect she has a strong influence on the inner nature of Crowley. She is receiving an exact sextile from mars and making a close sextile to Pluto&apos; both minor aspects but bringing both planets greater signification to his life. It is curious that the next aspect the moon makes in her course is a sextile with Saturn - this also shows increasing importance of Saturn in his life. Any short reading of Crowley would be inundated with saturnian symbolism such as BABALON, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelemapedia.org/index.php/Scarlet_Woman&quot;&gt; the scarlet women &lt;/a&gt; and matters too lengthy to go into here. 
  &lt;br /&gt; The moon being in the 8th and her close aspect with Pluto again reaffirms the importance of the symbolism of death and the mysteries of sexual union.  
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The 9th house is Aries, ruled by an exalted mars in the 6th. He has his MC point and the north node here signifying an importance of philosophy, spirituality and religion in his career. being ruled by mars it repeats the signification of hard laborious work, something that any serious study requires. Crowley&apos;s ability to stay up for days on end writing became great boons to his career. He claims in &lt;i&gt;Liber DCCXI Energized Enthusiasm&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;br /&gt; &quot;I wrote “Tannhauser,” complete from conception to execution, in sixty-seven consecutive hours. I was unconscious of the fall of nights and days, even after stopping; nor was there any reaction of fatigue. This work was written when I was twenty-four years old, immediately on the completion of an orgie which would normally have tired me out.&quot; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 
 
 
 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//2025/01/22/crowley/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//2025/01/22/crowley/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ross Ulbricht pardoned: transits</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Ross Ulbricht pardoned: transits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; &lt;u&gt;1st:&lt;/u&gt; day of arrest&lt;br /&gt;&lt;u&gt;2nd:&lt;/u&gt; profection years &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/Ross/prison.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;day of the arrest&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ross/prison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;  
   &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/Ross/p.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;profection years&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ross/p.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On oct. 1 2013, Ross Ulbricht was arrested at 29 years old. 29 is in a 6th house &lt;a href=&quot;https://theastrologypodcast.com/transcripts/ep-153-annual-profections-an-ancient-time-lord-technique/&quot;&gt; profection year&lt;/a&gt; meaning that transits through his 6th house of Leo are more important during this time. We see mars conjoined with the moon in Leo - and this is making a square to his natal mars in scorpio. This is a major transit for him that only happened once during this year. Mars cut him away from his work(6th house) and led to his imprisonment &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Ross&apos; natal chart&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/Ross/ross_natal.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ross/ross_natal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at his natal chart we see the ruler of his 5th house, the moon, in the 12th of isolation. his creative drive flows towards isolation - he was imprisoned for the website he created, literally isolated. Ross Ulbricht at the time of his release was 40 years old. this is a 5th house profection year, the sign of cancer ruled by the moon. This makes the moon and her transits more important as well as transits through the sign of cancer. As you can see in the pardoned chart, mars was retrograde in cancer and the moon was in a sign based applying trine to mars from scorpio. further strengthening mars - the moon is often seen as a trigger for events, she represents the body and things that happen to the body. It is also of note that mars in cancer is making a close trine to his natal mars in scorpio. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  
  &lt;h5&gt; &lt;u&gt;1st:&lt;/u&gt; time of pardon&lt;br /&gt;&lt;u&gt;2nd:&lt;/u&gt; 2024 solar return &lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
   &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/Ross/ross_pardon.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;time of pardon&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ross/ross_pardon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;

  
  &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/Ross/SR2024.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;2024 solar return&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ross/SR2024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;When looking at someones solar return for the year there are many important points such as the natal ascendent and lord, the SR ascendent and lord, the moon and her aspects, the profection year lord (and much more.) I am going to focus on a few interesting points. In his 2024 solar return, which he is still within, we find the SR ascendent to be scorpio, indicating the importance of mars and his transits. This is fascinating because mars is in the SR 5th house closely conjunct his natal ascendant. Because he has a night sect natal chart with mars in their own domicle they are not as malefic and in this case has clearly indicated good fortune in matters of the self. Don&apos;t forget he is in a 5th house profection year and it was when mars was in his natal 5th house of cancer that he was released. &lt;br /&gt;
I find the venus saturn conjunction in the SR 5th fascinating as he was pardoned during the next venus saturn conjunction in the same sign. This is also something to look for in solar returns, any aspects that will happen again during the course of the year - especially if they are angular. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//2025/01/21/ross_pardon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//2025/01/21/ross_pardon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>sweetpotato.press birth chart analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;sweetpotato.press birth chart analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;click to enlarge&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&quot;ca&quot; href=&quot;/img/na.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/na.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
decided to look at the chart for the time I purchased the domain name and was surprised to see its relevance. lets talk about it. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
this is a day time chart, with cancer rising and the ruler of the 1st in the 3rd. communications is integral to the health and well being of the body of sweetpotato.press(spp). the moon here is in her joy, the 3rd house is also called the house of the goddess. it is the place of ritual, daily observances, and divination. its the house that describes how the native talks and by what methods. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the moon is in generally good condition making a close but separating trine to her ruler mercury in the 7th house, she is happily placed in the night sector of the chart, she is receiving a superior square from jupiter and an opposition from venus. although we also see mars making a superior sextile, an opposition from saturn, she is in a cadent house, and she is waning.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the moon is coprescent with both the IC point and the south node. communications are not only important to the body but they also form the foundational point. the ground from which spp walks. the voice in all forms is extremely important! the south node brings mystery, a hidden place that the moon must soon cross- the den of the dragon - we can presume spp will be communicating difficult or shaded topics. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
overall the 3rd house is in moderately good condition and the moon is able to fulfill her signification as goddess with strong support from her ruler mercury. she can dive into the small details bringing to body the occult, religious rites, divination and dreams. all very important topics to spp! within which we wish to bring to earth the words that whirl inside. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the second house of finances is leo ruled by the sun in the 7th. we see that spp makes money from one on one interaction with others. appropriate for a site that offers birth chart readings. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the fourth house of home and foundations, secret things, ancestors and endings is ruled by venus in the 9th of spirituality. i think its fair to say that spp is building itself on a foundation of spirituality, philosophy, astrology and the occult. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 5th house of good fortune and creativity is mars in the 1st - having fun and being creative is greatly important to spp but may also bring difficulties being ruled by mars in their fall in a day chart. we could say creativity is extremely important but spp may take creative liberties that are at odds with reality in a quest towards a dream. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 6th house of hard work and illness is ruled by jupiter in the 12th - hard work flows towards isolation.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 7th house of other people, relationships is ruled by the 9th of spirituality - apt for a site wanting to bring the beauty of Hellenistic astrology to others and opening up their services to provide readings. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 8th house of shared finances and death is ruled by saturn in the 9th. there is a point of tension here! this house goes unseen and unmanaged 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
in the 9th house we have a smorgasbord. some may even call it a stelium but im less inclined. the 9th house is ruled by jupiter in the 12th. that&apos;s right, we are diving into our sorrows using philosophy, astrology, and spiritualism. we pull from the very depths of the hidden psyche, the abyss, our capability for spiritual knowledge and structure. it is the highest ambition to explore these hidden realms and bring them forward to the most visible point - the MC. the career and public presence of spp. it is within this house we have the part of fortune, venus, saturn, the MC, neptune and the north node. its a heavy hitting house and one that looks broadly, deeply, and internally being in the ocean like sign of pisces. it is the desire, the boundary, and the dissolving force tinged by the dragons head who is always looking for more. a lucky place that steers spp in their proper direction. with the close connection between an exalted venus and saturn we can only hope and expect a kinky flair that isnt afraid to touch on the underworld of sexual taboo -indeed venus here is out of bounds with a declination of -23, 41&apos; greatly indicating a venus that pushes beyond her usual. a young exuberant and extravagant evening star venus just barely passed her greatest elongation. this is pure luxury. this is the goddess Inanna decked out in all 7 parts of her dress fully decedent yet she is feeling the urge to go deep, the underworld calls and she will soon answer. and here she is with an old man, closely connected and in love saturn heightens her sexual prowess. there are no stops to the exhilaration between such morbid marriage - an indescribable age gap and they reveal in their savant dereliction. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
we see venus here exalted and in her own triplicity. it is this area of life that spp gains honor, recognition, and a following and its through venus&apos; extravagance that spp shines. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 10th house is the independent sign of aries, ruled by mars in the 1st house. the career of spp is to be themselves. lol. of course we too find difficulties here - an overreactive yet inward mars given full reign of the all powerful 10th house angle. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 11th house of community, friends, and good spirit is taurus, ruled by venus in the 9th house. further asserting the importance of spiritual topics - we also see uranus here giving a revelatory and unique flair- much like the out of bounds venus. spp can expect sudden changes and eccentric character from their community and shared dreams. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
the 12th house is gemini, ruled by mercury in the 7th. for better or worse our sorrows, isolation, questionable mental state and dark unseen abyss will be spread to those most closely in contact with spp. beware? or enjoy the hidden as it comes to light in a sporadic, sociable way. there is certainly tension here as mercury is unable to aspect the 12th house - the weight of the terrible and unending depth of the psyche may cause overwhelm for those within her bowels. jupiter here serves to increase this expansionary weight into the infinite (bounds) of reality. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;the part of fortune&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
lets go a step further and see what other reoccurring significations we may find. the lot of fortune, not only is it generally demarcating a lucky area of the natives life it reaffirms the body. if the birth chart is the cosmos the part of fortune is its influence on the actual body - it is herein we can revolve our chart- setting the part of fortune as the ascendant and marking its house as the first what do we find? 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
pisces is now the first house, they are ruled by jupiter in gemini. the fourth from fortune. here we see that the body of spp is their foundation. the website reaffirms itself. there is an importance of private matters, secret things, and foundations to the body of spp. which indeed, one of the goals of spp is to reaffirm the importance of foundations in practice. the missing culture in the west and one way to build that while freeing oneself from the dogma of old - yet still relying on its myth and grandeur to reach to new heights. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 2nd house, aires, is ruled by mars in the 5th. fun and creativity is important to monetary matters. money and finances flow towards creation. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 3rd house, taurus. is ruled by the 1st house pisces. and what fun, we see again a strong link between the 1st and 3rd just as we did in the natal chart but here its reversed. not only is spp conversing they are being conversed with. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 4th house, gemini, is ruled by mercury in the 11th. there is a disconnect here between the foundation and community - it very well could be a place of tension but lets be real, when has anyone&apos;s personal foundation worked for another? while it is good to have a place to jump eventually one must build their own walls from their personal inspiration. jupiter here in their own bounds shows that despite being cut off from their ruler they are still able to set their own terms. so while spp may love their community they said to get bent!!! we doing our own shit. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 5th house is cancer ruled by the moon in the 7th of virgo. spp brings fun and creativity to those in close connection to them. but again we see struggle with mars in their fall flavoring this house. perhaps spp is having a little bit TOO much fun without regard for others. woops. :3 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 6th is leo, ruled by the sun in the 11th. we do again see a point of tension here. the sun is unable to see their own house of leo. perhaps herein lies the cry of an artist and their work unshown. the difficulty of a community only seeing whats visible. or maybe im yanking my own chain. ;3 but none the less the hard work flows towards community so you best believe its all love (and a desire to be paid... buy a birth chart reading!)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 7th is virgo, ruled by mercury in the 11th. the relationships of spp flow towards its community. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
vettius valens says one can look to the 8th from fortune to understand the nature of ones death and that is just what we are going to do. the 8th house is libra ruled by venus in the 1st. perhaps the infinite weight of the abyss will become unbearable and the plug will have to be pulled by me, the writer. or perhaps the own weight of its unbridled sexuality will  be scorned by the general populace into a forced close. we can only here laugh at the possibilities. everything is temporary and this knowledge may be too. :p
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 9th house is scorpio ruled by mars in the 5th. again highlighting the trouble we might be in from having too much fun with the serious topic of spirituality and philosophy. hehe
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 10th house sagittarius is ruled by jupiter in the 4th. we bring the foundation forward as a piece not just for me but for yall too. the secrets and floor rise to the ceiling. don&apos;t get crushed!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the 11th house is capricorn ruled by saturn in the 1st. the community flows towards spp- of course. as im the one writing the articles here! id hope as much! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
and finally the 12th house. aquarius, ruled by the 1st. again we see the topics of sorrows, isolation, and the dark deep that exists beyond the surface being shewn by spp themselves. 

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

other fun points of note. the prenatal syzygy is a new moon in the angular 1st house. the triplicity lords of the sun are venus in the 9th and the moon in the 3rd with a moderating by mars in the 1st. seems spp is drowning in their own sorrows too. 


&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//2025/01/18/sweetpotato/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//2025/01/18/sweetpotato/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>missing culture: the search for god</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;missing culture: the search for god&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Both vedic and chinese astrology have close cultural ties treated with respect by its practitioners, a point that is lacking in modern western astrology. The recent renaissance of translated texts of hellenistic astrology changes this. bringing in a wealth of cultural influence and history that the christian church tried to wash away (despite themselves being heavily inspired) we are then incredibly lucky to live in a time where these ancient texts have managed to come down to us. it is from these ancients of western society that enables the building of a foundation and ethic from which to reach, a point within that one can take pride in. it is possible to live, thrive, and have spiritual connection free of worship and the guilt of modern religions with their fear of hell, karma and moralist interpretations of evil. an awareness of who influenced our thought patterns to this day and why western society thinks and reasons the way they do. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Plato, in his timaeus states &quot; ... The visibility of day and night, of months and the circling years, of equinoxes and solstice, resulted in the invention of number, gave us the concept of time, and made it possible for us to enquire into the nature of the universe.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There is a consistent whirling in all things but the bodies in the stars give consistency unlike any other - its limited scope giving the ability for lush interpretation free from uneeded noise. one could read the blades of grass but with millions flowing the words are not easily reducable to a consistent movement shown in a chart willed by the stories and archteypes that subsist through our culture and consciousness. a mercurial slice of time laid flat to celebrate the great moment of birth - an ancient photograph of the forces that move humanity through the cosmos just for you, a living breathing star on earth
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//2025/01/17/missingculture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//2025/01/17/missingculture/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
